<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<taxonomy version="1.0" namespace="rogue-herbalist">
    <taxon slug="immune-support" type="primary" hierarchical="true">
        <title>Immune Support &amp; Infection Resistance</title>
        <sub-title>Natural Defenses &amp; Seasonal Wellness</sub-title>
        <description>Products that support healthy immune system function and resistance to infections</description>
        <meta>
            <chebi-roles>immunomodulator,antioxidant,antimicrobial</chebi-roles>
            <npclassifier>beta-glucans,phenolic_compounds,polysaccharides</npclassifier>
            <chpa-category>immune_support</chpa-category>
            <fda-claim>Supports immune system function</fda-claim>
        </meta>
        <taxon slug="daily-immune" type="subcategory">
            <title>Daily Immune Maintenance</title>
            <description>Foundational immune support for everyday wellness. Products designed for consistent, long-term use to maintain healthy immune system function, build resilience, and support the body's natural defense mechanisms throughout the year.</description>
        </taxon>
        <taxon slug="seasonal-support" type="subcategory">
            <title>Seasonal &amp; Cold/Flu Support</title>
            <description>Targeted support during cold and flu season or at the first sign of illness. Fast-acting formulations to boost immune response, reduce symptom duration, and help the body fight off seasonal challenges and upper respiratory infections.</description>
        </taxon>
        <taxon slug="antiviral-herbs" type="subcategory">
            <title>Antiviral &amp; Antibacterial Herbs</title>
            <description>Potent antimicrobial botanicals with documented antiviral and antibacterial properties. Natural alternatives to support the body's ability to resist and fight various pathogens, including viruses, bacteria, and other microorganisms.</description>
        </taxon>
        <taxon slug="mushroom-immune" type="subcategory">
            <title>Mushroom Immune Complexes</title>
            <description>Medicinal mushroom formulations rich in beta-glucans and immunomodulating compounds. Includes reishi, turkey tail, shiitake, and other fungi known for deep immune support, cancer prevention, and overall vitality enhancement.</description>
        </taxon>
        <taxon slug="childrens-immune" type="subcategory">
            <title>Children's Immune Support</title>
            <description>Gentle, kid-friendly immune support formulations with age-appropriate dosing. Tasty syrups, gummies, and chewables designed to support developing immune systems, reduce sick days, and keep children healthy during school and play.</description>
        </taxon>
    </taxon>
    <taxon slug="gut-health" type="primary" hierarchical="true">
        <title>Gut Health &amp; Digestion</title>
        <sub-title>Digestive Comfort &amp; Microbiome Balance</sub-title>
        <description>Products supporting healthy digestion and gut microbiome</description>
        <meta>
            <chebi-roles>digestive_aid,hepatoprotectant,prebiotic,probiotic</chebi-roles>
            <npclassifier>iridoids,sesquiterpene_lactones,oligosaccharides</npclassifier>
            <chpa-category>digestive_health</chpa-category>
            <fda-claim>Supports healthy digestion and gut function</fda-claim>
        </meta>
        <taxon slug="digestive-support" type="subcategory">
            <title>General Digestive Support</title>
            <description>Broad-spectrum digestive aids for overall gut health, including enzymes, bitters, and gentle herbs that support digestion, reduce bloating, and improve nutrient absorption for everyday digestive comfort.</description>
        </taxon>
        <taxon slug="digestive-bitters" type="subcategory">
            <title>Digestive Bitters &amp; Stimulants</title>
            <description>Traditional bitter herbs that stimulate digestive juices, improve appetite, and enhance the body's natural digestive processes. Includes artichoke, dandelion, gentian, and other classic digestive tonics.</description>
        </taxon>
        <taxon slug="probiotic-support" type="subcategory">
            <title>Probiotic &amp; Prebiotic Support</title>
            <description>Beneficial bacteria and their supporting nutrients to maintain healthy gut microbiome balance, improve immune function, and support overall digestive wellness through targeted microbial therapy.</description>
        </taxon>
        <taxon slug="stomach-acid" type="subcategory">
            <title>Stomach Acid &amp; Enzyme Support</title>
            <description>Natural support for healthy stomach acid production and digestive enzyme function, addressing low stomach acid, improving protein digestion, and supporting optimal nutrient breakdown and absorption.</description>
        </taxon>
    </taxon>
</taxonomy>
